Guide to the Richard Henry Gregory papers, 1905-1910
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Richard Henry Gregory papers 1905-1910
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Gregory, Richard Henry.
27 items.
Tobacconist, of Tarboro, N.C., and employee of the British-American Tobacco Company in China, 1905-1935.
Diaries and photographs from Gregory's travels in China, 1905-1906, as an employee of the British-American Tobacco Company. Includes material on travels to Shanghai, Hankow, and the provinces of Honan, Hunan, Hupeh, and Kiangsi, including descriptions of the countryside and customs, and of tobacco culture in the region.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
Gift, 1974
Biographical Note
Richard Henry Gregory, tobacconist of Tarboro, N.C., traveled to China from 1905 to 1906 on behalf of the British-American Tobacco Company. Gregory served as head of the company's Leaf Department in China. In 1912, Gregory married Hattie B. Arrington and together the couple raised two children while living in Shanghai--John, who died during childhood diptheria, and Jane. Gregory made his home in China until his retirement in 1935.
Collection Overview
Diaries and photographs from Gregory's travels in China, 1905-1906, as an employee of the British-American Tobacco Company. Includes material on travels to Shanghai, Hankow, and the provinces of Honan, Hunan, Hupeh, and Kiangsi, including descriptions of the countryside and customs, and of tobacco culture in the region.
Subject Headings
These and related materials may be found under the following headings in online catalogs.
Tobacco industry -- China
British-American Tobacco Co. (China) -- Employees
China -- Description and travel
Related Material
Hattie A. Gregory Papers, 1904-1934
J.Y. Joyner Library, East Carolina University
Jane Gregory Marrow Oral History Interview, January 26, 1976
J.Y. Joyner Library, East Carolina University
British-American Tobacco Company Records, 1842-1929
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Contents of Collection
- Diaries and Letter, 1905-1906
  Two diaries kept by Richard Henry Gregory during his travels in China, 1905-1906. Also included is a two-part typed copy of the June-August, 1906 diary that includes photographs with typed captions, and a letter from Gregory to "My Dear Katie," dated January 12, 1906.
  - Travel diary of Richard Henry Gregory on his first trip to China, April 23, 1905 - June 2, 1905 (Box 1)
  - Diary of Richard Henry Gregory of British American Tobacco Co., June-August, 1906 (Box 1)
  - Part I: Typed copy of diary of Richard Henry Gregory of British American Tobacco Co., June-August, 1906 (with photographs and captions) (Box 1)
    Diary includes photographs (with typed captions) of Gregory's travels in China.
  - Part II: Typed copy of diary of Richard Henry Gregory of British American Tobacco Co., June-August, 1906 (with photographs and captions) (Box 1)
  - Letter from R. H. Gregory in Shanghai to "My dear Katie," January 12, 1906 (Box 1)
- Photographs, 1905-1940
  Series includes photographs of British American Tobacco Company cigarette factories, operations, employees, and executives probably in Hankow, China.
  - British-American Tobacco Company leaf department, Hankow, China, 1910 (Box 1)
    Back Row (left to right): E. B. Gregory, H. E. Morton, W. O. Moore; Front Row (left to right): S. P. Clement, R. H. Gregory, John Covington, Wright
  - Jane on tennis court (Box 1)
  - R. H. Gregory and William Morris, circa 1940 (Box 1)
    Taken in Rocky Mount, N.C., probably by EC Stocker.
  - British-American Tobacco Company cigarette factory, probably in Hankow, China. (Box 1)
  - British-American Tobacco Company cigarette factory, probably in Hankow, China. (Box 1)
  - British-American Tobacco Company cigarette factory, probably in Hankow, China. (Box 1)
  - British-American Tobacco Company cigarette factory, probably in Hankow, China. (Box 1)
  - British-American Tobacco Company cigarette factory, probably in Hankow, China. (Box 1)
  - British-American Tobacco Company cigarette factory, probably in Hankow, China. (Box 1)
  - British-American Tobacco Company cigarette factory, probably in Hankow, China. (Box 1)
  - British-American Tobacco Company cigarette factory, probably in Hankow, China. (Box 1)
  - British-American Tobacco Company cigarette factory, probably in Hankow, China. (Box 1)
  - British-American Tobacco Company cigarette factory, probably in Hankow, China. (Box 1)
  - British-American Tobacco Company cigarette factory, probably in Hankow, China. (Box 1)
  - British-American Tobacco Company cigarette factory, probably in Hankow, China. (Box 1)
  - British-American Tobacco Company cigarette factory, probably in Hankow, China. (Box 1)
  - British-American Tobacco Company cigarette factory, probably in Hankow, China. (Box 1)
  - British-American Tobacco Company cigarette factory, probably in Hankow, China. (Box 1)
  - British-American Tobacco Company cigarette factory, probably in Hankow, China. (Box 1)
  - British-American Tobacco Company cigarette factory, probably in Hankow, China. (Box 1)